<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andy Sigler</title>
    <description>I make things.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Nodela</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Roland-Modela is a discontued micro-milling machine, and students at &lt;a href=&quot;http://itp.nyu.edu&quot;&gt;ITP&lt;/a&gt; use it to mill PCBs from copper clad plates. It’s a well made machine, but it’s software package is terrible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/roland.png&quot; alt=&quot;roland-modela&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to edit the executable files manually in text editors, and of course we didn’t know what we were doing. Not to mention, the bed was made from steel, so all copper plates were held down (unevenly) with messy double-sided tape. We were breaking bits like crazy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was excited about milling PCBs, but this was the only micro milling machine I had access to. So I made a simple interface using Javascript, and designed a new bed from delrin, and now I can cut straight from an Eagle file without breaking bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/roland_delrin.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;roland-modela&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-interface&quot;&gt;The Interface&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a screenshot if the interface. It allows you to jog the head around, in order to select your cut’s origin (impossible until recently). It also loads preset speed and plunge values for different bits, so that each bit is used at it’s most optimal settings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/interface-nodela.png&quot; alt=&quot;nodela-interface&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To load your file, simply drag the Eagle &lt;code&gt;.brd&lt;/code&gt; file onto the interface, and it will parse our all the layers that contain toolpath lines (drawn with &lt;code&gt;WIRES&lt;/code&gt;). Then it’s just a matter of selecting the correct layer and bit size before pressing print!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;links-and-tutorials&quot;&gt;Links and Tutorials&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software can be found on &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/andysigler/nodela&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. Check out the README for installation instructions and getting in running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FAQ for the Roland-Modela and interface can be found on ITP’s shop website. (http://shop.itp.nyu.edu/machines/cnc-milling-machines/roland-modela-mdx-20)[Here is a direct link] to the Modela’s page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have also recorded to video tutorials on using the Modela. The first is on how to prepare your Eagle file to be milled, and the second is a walkthrough of cutting that same file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/119003450&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/119725323&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of digital frabrication and circuit prototyping machines hitting the market these days, so I know this hack for making a discotinued machine usable won’t last long. But, if you use it and like it, please let me know, and also if there are any changes needed :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hardware/nodela/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/hardware/nodela/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Patchbay Interface</title>
        <description>&lt;style&gt;
	#routerContainer {
		position:relative;
		display:block-inline;
		background-color:rgb(79,79,79);
	}
	#patchbayTitle {
		color:rgb(79,79,79);
	}
	canvas{
		display:inline;
		position:absolute;
		left:0px;
		top:0px;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/hammer.min.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/websocketStuff.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/canvasStuff.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/touchStuff.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/cord.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/port.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/arc.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/circle.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/mouse.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/js/patchbay/initPatchbay.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Patchbay is a graphical interface, developed for my 2014 master’s thesis at ITP. It was designed to greatly simplify multi-device interactions, and allows users to make and break links between wireless objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skip ahead to &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/96851567#t=5m10s&quot;&gt;5:10&lt;/a&gt; to see my explanation of the Patchbay interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/96851567&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term Patchbay refers to a piece of equipment found in most recording studios. Patchbays are boxes that live in a studio, and an engineer will wire the audio inputs and outputs from all their equipment into it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/patchbay.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;patchbay&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What it provides is convenience in connecting their equipment, by have one central place to do it. The studio’s engineer is now able to quickly design sounds using the links between her gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;demo&quot;&gt;Demo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A working demo of the Patchbay can be found below. It’s interactive! Rotate the arcs to view different project, and connect inputs and output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;routerContainer&quot; style=&quot;margin-bottom:1.5rem&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div id=&quot;patchbayTitle&quot;&gt;PatchBay&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;canvas id=&quot;canvas&quot;&gt;&lt;/canvas&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The devices you see, and their corresponding &lt;code&gt;INPUTs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;OUTPUTs&lt;/code&gt;, are actualy toys and objects developed for my 2014 thesis. It was a lot of fun playing with the connections between them :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;an-interface-for-interop&quot;&gt;An Interface for Interop&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What the Patchbay assumes (and all patching intefaces for that matter, digital and physical) is that all nodes in the network are interoperable, meaning that they are able to seamlessly communicate with each other. The people who made them have come to some agreement over how they will communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Patchbay’s role in such an ecosystem is to simply say “This talk to That.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each device has what’s called &lt;code&gt;INPUTs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;OUTPUTs&lt;/code&gt;. For a simple example, imagine two devices. The first has three buttons, the second has two lights. The first device has three &lt;code&gt;INPUTs&lt;/code&gt;, and the second has two &lt;code&gt;OUTPUTs&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Patchbay, I could connect button #2 to light #1. This would be done by connecting the device’s &lt;code&gt;INPUT&lt;/code&gt; #2 to the other’s &lt;code&gt;OUTPUT&lt;/code&gt; #1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/patchbay_make.gif&quot; alt=&quot;patchbay_make&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I no longer want that button to control that light, I erase the connection on the interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/patchbay_break.gif&quot; alt=&quot;patchbay_break&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a simple interface come constraints. The Patchbay is for devices that share only simple values between them. Buttons and lights are a good example: the button could send a &lt;code&gt;1&lt;/code&gt; when pressed, and a &lt;code&gt;0&lt;/code&gt; when released. These numbers would be received by the light, and it would interpret them as meaning “Turn ON” and “Turn OFF.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;too-many-things&quot;&gt;Too Many Things&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The past few years, I have seen a growing interest in connected devices, and how to best interact with an Internet of Things on a day-to-day bases. “Patching” interfaces have arose, ranging from simple I/O mapping, to more richly featured environments for controlling a network’s data flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/spacebrew.png&quot; alt=&quot;spacebrew&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.spacebrew.cc/&quot;&gt;Spacebrew&lt;/a&gt; - a framework for mapping simple I/O over a WebSocket connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/node-red.png&quot; alt=&quot;node-red&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.spacebrew.cc/&quot;&gt;Node-RED&lt;/a&gt; - a framework for connecting devices, APIs and online services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these interfaces have one serious design flaw: they become easily over-crowded and difficult to use once the network grows. The more devices that are displayed, the more concentration a user must put into navigating and using one of these interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/zombie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;zombies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Patchbay hides most of this complexity, using its adaptive circular design. When a new device comes within range of the interface, it will be represented by a new arc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By rotating either circle, you are allowed to see only a couple of the devices’ &lt;code&gt;INPUTs&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;OUTPUTs&lt;/code&gt;. This allows the user to focus on only the devices they are currently interacting with, freeing them to look up and experience physical sensations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-it-was-made&quot;&gt;How it was Made&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Patchbay is an HTML5 graphical interface, designed to work on any device that supports modern web technologies. All animations are done an a Canvas element using custom Javascript. The only framework used was &lt;a href=&quot;http://hammerjs.github.io/&quot;&gt;Hammer.js&lt;/a&gt;, a Javascript library for handling both mouse and touch events for tablets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my thesis, the interface was connected over a WebSocket connection to a local &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodejs.org/&quot;&gt;NodeJS&lt;/a&gt; server. This NodeJS server was constantly scanning for surrounding devices, and relaying the space’s state on the interface. The decision to run a NodeJS server was made because my devices were all communicating using the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hoperf.com/rf/fsk_module/RFM12B.htm&quot;&gt;RFm12b radio&lt;/a&gt;, operating at 433MHz, and using the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jcw/jeelib&quot;&gt;Arduino library from JeeNode&lt;/a&gt;. Smartphones sadly do not support these frequencies, so I fellback to running a local server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for future implementations I would like to use Bluetooth 4.0. This would allow devices to communicate over broadcasted, stateless communication channels, while being able to communicate directly with a user’s smartphone, tablet, or laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download the Patchbay from (https://github.com/andySigler/patchbay)[GitHub]. The repo comes with the NodeJS server, HTML5 inteface, and Arduino Library for using the RFm12b.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/patchbay/patchbay-interface/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/patchbay/patchbay-interface/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>NodeJS + Yun</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Below are the steps to get NodeJS up and running on the Arduino Yun. This tutorial assumes you have already connected the Yun to your network, and have a basic understanding of NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final steps (red section) of this tutorial are optional and should be taken with caution. They show how to disable Bridge on the Yun, in order to allow NodeJS to speak directly with the Arduino side of the board using node-serialport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This, however, means you can only access the Linux side of the board over the network. If you do not have control over the network between your computer and Yun, you will not be able to connect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;update-the-yuns-image&quot;&gt;Update the Yun’s image&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To do all the following, make sure you have updated your Yun to the latest image. This to to allow your Yun to have is disk space expanded in the next step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/YunSysupgrade&quot;&gt;Instructions on updating the Yun’s image&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;expand-disk-space-with-sd-card&quot;&gt;Expand disk space with SD card&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will be moving the Yun’s operating system and memory onto a micro-sd card, so that we have enough room to install and run NodeJS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Tutorial/ExpandingYunDiskSpace&quot;&gt;Instructions on expanding the Yun’s disk space&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;install-node-and-node-modules-with-opkg&quot;&gt;Install Node and node-modules with opkg&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an updated Yun image and more memory, we can install Node using opkg (the Yun’s package management system). Be sure the Yun is connected to the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the following line into the Yun to prepare opkg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;opkg update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After each call to opkg, you should see some lines about downloading and installing some files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next install NodeJS with the following line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;opkg install node&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may take a few moments. After it’s finished, install the pre-compiled node-modules using opkg.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;opkg install node-ws 
opkg install node-serialport&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few other pre-compiled node-modules you can install through opkg. All modules are installed globally, so there is no need to ever run npm (especially because npm doesn’t work on the Yun…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;add-sftp-to-transfer-files&quot;&gt;Add SFTP to transfer files&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Uploading files to the Yun is much faster if you don’t have to turn it off every time. To do this, we have enable our Yun to be accessed over SFTP. Now, applications like CyberDuck can connect to and upload files to your Yun&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter the following line to install the SFTP package, and now you can connect to it using an FTP client like CyberDuck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;opkg update 
opkg install openssh-sftp-server&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In CyberDuck, connect with SFTP, port 22, username ‘root’, and the server-name being your Yun’s IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/cyberDuck_yun.png&quot; alt=&quot;cyberDuck_yun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I store all the node and web files on the micro-sd card, at &lt;code&gt;/mnt/sda1/arduino/node&lt;/code&gt;. “sda1” is the external memory, “arduino” is a folder that should already exist, and “node” is a folder I created to store my Node scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/cyberDuck_yun_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;cyberDuck_yun_2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can upload and run NodeJS scripts on your Yun! See the below link for you can get NodeJS and the Arduino side of the Yun talking with Bridge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigoe.com/pcomp/code/arduinowiring/1216/#more-1216&quot;&gt;Node.js on the Arduino Yun&lt;/a&gt; - Tom Igoe’s example for getting NodeJS and the ATmega32U4 to communicate with Bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;give-the-ethernet-port-a-static-ip&quot;&gt;Give the ethernet port a static IP&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my mind, the biggest disadvantage of removing Bridge from the Yun, is that you are taking away the ability to access the Linino through the ATmega32U4. This is especially helpul during initial setup, and while configuring the Yun’s network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give some added security, I have chosen to give my Yun’s ethernet port a static, never changing IP address. With this, I can ssh into the Yun over an ethernet cable, using the following steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will edit a file to change the Yun’s network settings. The nano command opens it in terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;nano /etc/config/network&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the error &lt;code&gt;Error opening terminal: xterm-256color.&lt;/code&gt;, the following worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;ln -s x /usr/share/terminfo/78 
export TERM=xterm-color 
nano /etc/config/network&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the part of the document that looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;config interface &amp;#39;wan&amp;#39;
   option iframe &amp;#39;eth1&amp;#39;
   option proto &amp;#39;dhcp&amp;#39;
   option metric &amp;#39;10&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And change it to look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;config interface &amp;#39;wan&amp;#39;
   option iframe &amp;#39;eth1&amp;#39;
   option &amp;#39;proto&amp;#39; &amp;#39;static&amp;#39;
   option &amp;#39;ipaddr&amp;#39; &amp;#39;192.168.0.200&amp;#39;
   option &amp;#39;netmask&amp;#39; &amp;#39;255.255.255.0&amp;#39;
   option &amp;#39;gateway&amp;#39; &amp;#39;192.168.0.1&amp;#39;
   option &amp;#39;dns&amp;#39; &amp;#39;192.168.0.1&amp;#39;
   option metric &amp;#39;10&amp;#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions on the bottom show how to Write Out (save the file), and Exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Write Out (save your changes), hit &lt;code&gt;CONTROL-O&lt;/code&gt;. It will ask if you want to save changes to this file, hit &lt;code&gt;ENTER&lt;/code&gt; to save. To Exit hit &lt;code&gt;CONTROL-X&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restart your Yun, and you will find it’s ethernet port has the permanent address &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.200&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to ssh into the Yun over an ethernet cable, your laptop’s ethernet IP address must share the same two first digits as the Yun’s IP. In this example, the laptop’s IP should beging width 192 and 168 in order for the two to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/staticEthernet_mac.png&quot; alt=&quot;staticEthernet_mac&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a Mac, I can go to &lt;code&gt;System Preferences &amp;gt; Network&lt;/code&gt;, select the ethernet port, and tell it to be a Manual IP Address (not DHCP). For example, I could set my laptop to be &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.42&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;disable-bridge-on-the-yun&quot;&gt;Disable Bridge on the Yun&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;alert-box radius alert&quot;&gt;
Warning: Proceed with Caution!
To disable Bridge and free the serial port between the Linux processor and the ATmega32U4, you simply have to comment out one line, and then restart the Yun. To bring Bridge back, simply uncomment the line, and restart the Yun.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open the file we must in edit in Terminal with the following command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;nano /etc/inittab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get the error &lt;code&gt;Error opening terminal: xterm-256color.&lt;/code&gt;, the following worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;ln -s x /usr/share/terminfo/78 
export TERM=xterm-color 
nano /etc/inittab&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nano command will open up a text editor in Terminal, where you can move around with the arrow keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the line that says this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;ttyATH0::askfirst:/bin/ash --login&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And comment it out with pound sign at the beginning, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;#ttyATH0::askfirst:/bin/ash --login&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instructions on the bottom show how to Write Out (save the file), and Exit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Write Out (save your changes), hit &lt;code&gt;CONTROL-O&lt;/code&gt;. It will ask if you want to save changes to this file, hit &lt;code&gt;ENTER&lt;/code&gt; to save. To Exit hit &lt;code&gt;CONTROL-X&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Restart your Yun, and Bridge will not run. Once again, simply uncomment the line to bring Bridge back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;modify-code-and-run&quot;&gt;Modify code and run&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Arduino on your Yun can now open a plain Serial connection to the Linux processor. However, it uses &lt;code&gt;Serial1&lt;/code&gt; instead of &lt;code&gt;Serial&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code&gt;Serial&lt;/code&gt; (without the 1) is connected to the micro-USB, and is used to upload code and communicate with a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So to begin in your setup(), your Arduino code should read:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c--&quot; data-lang=&quot;c++&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;115200&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; 
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;){}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to read and write, continue using &lt;code&gt;Serial1&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c--&quot; data-lang=&quot;c++&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;while&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;available&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()){&lt;/span&gt;
   &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;read&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;());&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;Serial1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;println&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any process running on Linux side of the board can access the Arduino’s serial port with the name &lt;code&gt;/dev/ttyATH0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now any NodeJS script using the node-serialport module can access the Atmel32u4 using port &lt;code&gt;/dev/ttyATH0&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andySigler/NodeJS_Yun_Example&quot;&gt;NodeJS_Yun_Example&lt;/a&gt; - Some example code, showing a NodeJS server mediating the connection between a browser and an Arduino.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/voodootikigod/node-serialport/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;Reference for node-serialport&lt;/a&gt; - Connect a Node script to the ATmega32U4&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/einaros/ws/blob/master/README.md&quot;&gt;Reference for node-ws&lt;/a&gt; - Run a WebSocket server on the Yun to have fast, real-time communication with a browser or other devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/arduino/openwrt-packages-yun/tree/master/arduino&quot;&gt;Node-modules available through opkg&lt;/a&gt; - the repo containing all pre-compiled node-modules for the Yun. Others include Noble, Bleno, and socket.io.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tigoe.com/pcomp/code/arduinowiring/1216/#more-1216&quot;&gt;Node.js on the Arduino Yun&lt;/a&gt; - Tom Igoe’s example for getting NodeJS and the ATmega32U4 to communicate with Bridge. Its a bit of a hack that uses the stdin and stdout of a process.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/teaching/nodejs-arduino-yun/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/teaching/nodejs-arduino-yun/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ITP Master&#39;s Thesis</title>
        <description>
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/how-to-make-the-internet-of-useless-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/how-to-make-the-internet-of-useless-things/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Noser</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Noser is a combination of musical instruments, exploring the real-time performance of timbre. Traditional instrumentation has explored changes in pitch, level, rhythm and timing for thousands of years. With computers and music synthesis, we can now explore the manipulation of a sound’s spectral shape and content through physical interaction. For my methods, I first used the combination of FFT convolution and the Touche sensing technique, and second, resonant filters modeling the human vocal tract. Convolution and vowel modeling, combined with physical interaction with the hands, has led to some interesting results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an earlier prototype of the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/74424188&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;278&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interface uses a multi-touch trackpad, proximity sensor, and flexible polycarbonite poles, all to allow the human hand to expressively perform vowel sounds. The fingers horizontal position moves the frequency of resonant bandpass filters, while their vertical position alters the filters’ Q.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/noser/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/noser/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Browser Tag</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;span8 offset3&quot; title=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot; name=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot; href=&quot;javascript:(function()%7Bvar%20bk%3D%7Bmouse:%7Bx:0,y:0%7D,imgCounter:0,allImages:%5B%5D,maxImages:500,maxWidth:500,minWidth:10,ratio:270/880,prev:0.5,slide:2,move:false,toggle:true,highestZ:100000,img:document.createElement(%22img%22)%7D%3Bbk.img.src%3D%22http://localhost:4000/images/btnc.png%22%3Bfunction%20cloneImage(a,f,d)%7Bvar%20c%3DgetWidth()%3Bif(c%3Cbk.minWidth)%7Bc%3D200%7Dvar%20b%3DMath.floor(c*bk.ratio)%3Bvar%20e%3Dbk.img.cloneNode(true)%3Be.style.position%3D%22absolute%22%3Be.style.width%3Dc%2B%22px%22%3Be.style.height%3Db%2B%22px%22%3Be.style.top%3D(f-(b/2))%2B%22px%22%3Be.style.left%3D(a-(c/2))%2B%22px%22%3Be.style.zindex%3Dbk.highestZ%2Bbk.imgCounter%3Bif(e.style.webkitTransform!%3D%3Dundefined)%7Be.style.webkitTransform%3D%22rotate(%22%2Bd%2B%22deg)%22%7Delse%7Bif(e.style.MozTransform!%3D%3Dundefined)%7Be.style.MozTransform%3D%22rotate(%22%2Bd%2B%22deg)%22%7Delse%7Bif(e.style.msTransform!%3D%3Dundefined)%7Be.style.msTransform%3D%22rotate(%22%2Bd%2B%22deg)%22%7Delse%7Bif(e.style.OTransform!%3D%3Dundefined)%7Be.style.OTransform%3D%22rotate(%22%2Bd%2B%22deg)%22%7Delse%7Bif(e.style.transform!%3D%3Dundefined)%7Be.style.transform%3D%22rotate(%22%2Bd%2B%22deg)%22%7D%7D%7D%7D%7De.id%3D%22img_%22%2Bbk.imgCounter%3Bbk.imgCounter%2B%2B%3Bdocument.body.appendChild(e)%7Dfunction%20getWidth()%7Bvar%20a%3D((Math.tan(((Math.random()*2)-1)*(Math.PI/4))%2B1)/2)%3Bbk.prev%3Dbk.prev%2B((a-bk.prev)/bk.slide)%3Breturn%20Math.floor((bk.prev*bk.maxWidth)%2Bbk.minWidth)%7Dwindow.onmousemove%3Dfunction(a)%7Bbk.mouse.x%3Da.pageX%3Bbk.mouse.y%3Da.pageY%3Bbk.move%3Dtrue%7D%3Bwindow.onclick%3Dfunction(a)%7Bbk.toggle%3D!bk.toggle%7D%3Bfunction%20findHighestZIndex()%7Bvar%20g%3D%5B%22div%22,%22p%22,%22img%22%5D%3Bvar%20f%3D0%3Bvar%20a%3Dg.length%3Bfor(var%20b%3D0%3Bb%3Ca%3Bb%2B%2B)%7Bvar%20c%3Ddocument.getElementsByTagName(g%5Bb%5D)%3Bfor(var%20e%3D0%3Be%3Cc.length%3Be%2B%2B)%7Bvar%20d%3Ddocument.defaultView.getComputedStyle(c%5Be%5D,null).getPropertyValue(%22z-index%22)%3Bif((d%3Ef)%26%26(d!%3D%22auto%22))%7Bf%3Dd%7D%7D%7Dbk.highestZ%3Df%7DsetInterval(function()%7Bif(bk.move%26%26bk.toggle)%7BcloneImage(bk.mouse.x,bk.mouse.y,Math.floor(Math.random()*80-40))%3Bbk.move%3Dfalse%7D%7D,100)%3BfindHighestZIndex()%3B%7D)()%3B&quot; alt=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img id=&quot;sticker&quot; width=&quot;360&quot; border=&quot;3&quot; title=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/btnc_fold.png&quot; name=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot; alt=&quot;BitTorrent-Sticker&quot; style=&quot;border:2px solid black&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instructions&quot;&gt;Instructions:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Drag&lt;/strong&gt; the sticker to your &lt;strong&gt;bookmark bar&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to any website and &lt;strong&gt;click&lt;/strong&gt; the “BitTorrent-Sticker” bookmarklet.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move&lt;/strong&gt; your cursor to start tagging the page, click to turn on/off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bookmarklet was my first and favorite thing I made while interning for &lt;strong&gt;BitTorrent&lt;/strong&gt; during the summer of 2013. It is a bookmarklet that, when pressed on any webpage, injects a small script to cover the page with the &lt;strong&gt;BitTorrent Is Not a Crime&lt;/strong&gt; campaign sticker. Simple and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/browser-tag/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/browser-tag/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ScreenRacer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Screen Racer is a multi-screen, online game, made with HTML5, Node.js, and WebSockets. Using the iPhone’s orientation as a controller, players send their helicopter through rough terrain, all spread across any number of connected web browsers. This allows Screen Racer’s landscape to depend on the physical placement of the screens. I have found it fun to place the screens in a circle, forcing the player to run in circles in order to keep up with their helicopter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;View the project on &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://github.com/andySigler/screenracer&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/screenracer/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/screenracer/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenLimbs</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/wov2sgdQe8Y&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Limbs Project, made up of Andy Sigler, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wk9.tumblr.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Will Canine&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.carlj.us/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Carl Jamilkowski&lt;/a&gt;, uses the body as a medium and means for expression. The Project uses electric muscle stimulation to control the limbs of the human body, leading to new forms of expressions, identity, and connections. The Open Limbs Project was created for the Biomechanics graduate course at ITP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is a video of Will hooked up to two stimulators, one controlled through tilting a smartphone, the other through moving the skeleton’s arm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/65162857&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;281&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenLimbs was shown in the ITP 2013 Spring Show, and somehow made it to the front page of Yahoo! news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;blank&quot; href=&quot;http://news.yahoo.com/blogs/this-could-be-big-abc-news/remote-control-body-184110077.html&quot;&gt;
	&lt;img style=&quot;width:70%&quot; src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/yahoo.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/openlimbs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/openlimbs/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Numbers on the Board</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Numbers on the Board is a sculptural installation, designed for the Manhattan-Henge events, during the months of May through July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manhatten-Henge is the solar phenomenon that occurs every summer in New York City, where two nights a year, the sunset perfectly aligns with the streets on Manhattan. This allows pedestrians to see the sunset over the horizon through the tall skyscrapers, and the sun can be seen through to the other side of Manhattan, into Brooklyn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To emphasis how special these moments of alignment are, myself, &lt;a href=&quot;http://johncapogna.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;John Capogna&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.allisonburtch.net/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Allison Burtch&lt;/a&gt; created a sound installation, designed to live on the Tudor Bridge on 42nd Street. Using the sonic alignment of polyphonic rhythms, Numbers on the Board uses five gears, each with 42, 43, 44, 45, and 46 teeth, to create an ever-evolving melody, and all notes perfectly align every 44 days. If started during the first occurrence of Manhatten-Henge, the gears would play for two months, and then aligning again during the exact moment of the second Manhatten-Henge, 44 days latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sculpture uses metal tongs, inspired by the African Mbira, to create a soothing, yet percussive melody. The Mbira is designed to perform polkyphonic melodies, and seems like a perfect fit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/numbers-on-the-board/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/numbers-on-the-board/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Foodable</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Foodable is an interactive table, designed for a NYC food event, and made in collaboration with &lt;a href=&quot;http://johncapogna.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;John Capogna&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://shilpanbhagat.com/site/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shilpan Bhagat&lt;/a&gt;. Using multiple sensing technologies, we allow diners to â€œplayâ€ with their food, while simultaneously learning about their dish and drink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/images/foodable_flow.jpg&quot; style=&quot;border-bottom:20px solid white&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2013 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/projects/foodable/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/projects/foodable/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
